Hello folks, welcome back to your most
anticipated pump of doom update. Good
news, pump of doom is now running.
Let's go take a look.
So, that only took nine days
and in the end
a lot of assistance from a very kind
person.
Now,
the way with the pump running we can
make some hydraulic pressure from a
standstill, which is what we want. So,
can now turn our attention to the TCU or
the TCM, whichever you prefer to to call
it. Now, in the
the little bit of in the AHP swapping
land there's kind of two ways that they
seem to do this.
One is to run with the existing TCM, so
there's a
circuit in there.
And they kind of
do some secret handshake stuff and
basically get it to run as if it were in
the parent vehicle.
And the second way is you cut this can
open
and replace the electronics in there
with a board like this one. This is just
one I
made up. It's kind of based on this one.
Let me get that out of here.
This one also comes with this kind of a
kind of a nifty cover.
And
it's basically like that.
So that board goes inside there.
And what that basically does is it
connects all of the valves and things
like the speed sensors and that
directly to the external connector. So
you can then control the valves with an
external control box.
Um
and that was the way that I was going to
go, to be honest. I was just going to
I'd have to change the design of this
board cuz this doesn't have the LIN
connection, for example, for the pump.
But other than that, it's fine.
Um
so that's the way I was going to go.
But I've been, obviously cuz I've been
working on the LIN and the pump, I was
having some thoughts. And so I want to
run this past you folks and see what you
think. Maybe there's kind of a forward
option here.
So I'm thinking, rather than having
a big kind of, you know, you have a
board you put in here and then you have
your external controller and harnesses
and all that good stuff.
Uh what if
instead, we actually designed our
open inverter TCM to go on that board.
Uh
we put our STM32, little power supply,
support circuitry on a valve driver
chip, which I have found.
It's uh by Maxim. It's a very small
chip, but it can literally drive all the
valves from a single part.
And we literally put a CAN transceiver
on that, a LIN transceiver to talk to
the pump if you're
using a hybrid one.
And then we basically put this
put the this board in there, in place of
the existing TCM.
And then
um
we can put this back into the gearbox
and then we just give it
ground 12 volts, CAN high, and CAN low
low and we can
you know, connect our web interface, we
can send commands to it, we can send
software updates and all that kind of
thing. So, that's where I'm thinking of
going, folks, because
even a board like that, we can easily
make six-layer now with JLC.
Um so, it would be well feasible, I
think, to do a
a kind of a hybrid of the two, if you
don't mind the pun. So, we push a new
TCM inside the TCM and then control that
via CAN externally.
So, that's kind of where my thoughts are
at the minute, folks. Uh let me know
what you think in the comments, please.
So, we'd have a
board like that, pretty much that size,
um but we'd have our components on on
here
for our STM32-based
TCM. So,
that's about it. As always, don't forget
to dislike this garbage.
Um don't subscribe. If you are
subscribed, unsubscribe.
Um
so, you don't have to be exposed to this
kind of nonsense any further.
Uh so, I'm going to go ahead in the next
episode, I'll get the CAN open on that
uh TCM that I have there on the bench. I
will start kind of working out what pins
we need to have on here and how it would
kind of work out. But, I think a little
board that size
with a 32F1,
CAN transceiver, LIN transceiver, a
little power supply, and one of those
Maxim
valve driver chips
would work quite well. So, don't know.
We'll
see what we can do. Anyway, I need to be
something different.
There you go. All right, folks. That's
enough of me talking nonsense.
So, until we see you next time then.
Happy TCM designing.